Inventory of O.41 - Collection of Lists and Documentation Regarding Those Who Perished and Those Who Were Persecuted During the Holocaust Period O.41
O.41 - Collection of Lists and Documentation Regarding Those Who Perished and Those Who Were Persecuted During the Holocaust Period
- Section of a registration book of the municipality of Paris including information regarding the death of Suzanne (Sabbi) Lahmi, from Marseille, in Birkenau, 10/10/1943, 13/04/1956-13/04/1956; The file was created by Mairie du IV Arrondissement; 1 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered
  Section of a registration book of the municipality of Paris including information regarding the death of Suzanne (Sabbi) Lahmi, from Marseille, in Birkenau, 10/10/1943
- Documentation regarding the fate of Emil and Charlota (Kirschbaumova) Liebhold, who were deported from Frankfurt am Main and perished in Theresienstadt, 1943, 11/07/1947-07/11/1947; 3 Personal documents Certification Death certificate Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/519
  Frankfurt am Main,Wiesbaden,Hesse-Nassau,Germany; Theresienstadt,Litomerice,Bohemia,Czechoslovakia
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by לנגיצקי רותי
  Documentation regarding the fate of Emil and Charlota (Kirschbaumova) Liebhold, who were deported from Frankfurt am Main and perished in Theresienstadt, 1943
- Certification by the Central Archive of the Ministry of Defense of the Soviet Union, that Aron Gulkarov, from Bukhara, was killed in action in Nagykallo, 30/10/1944, and that Mikhail Gulkarov is Missing in Action (MIA), 02/11/1942, 16/08/1988-16/08/1988; 3 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered persons Original; O.41/543
  Jewish soldiers in the Red Army; Bukhara,Bukhara City,Bukhara,Uzbekistan (USSR); Nagykallo,Szabolcs,<>,Hungary
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by גולקרוב פנחס
  Certification by the Central Archive of the Ministry of Defense of the Soviet Union, that Aron Gulkarov, from Bukhara, was killed in action in Nagykallo, 30/10/1944, and that Mikhail Gulkarov is Missing in Action (MIA), 02/11/1942
- Documentation regarding Mosie and Marie (Rothova) Aron, deported from Saint Gilles to Malines, 1943, date empty; 3 Personal documents Card file Record of deportees xerox; O.41/507
  Deportation from Belgium; Saint Gilles,Brabant,<>,Belgium; Malines,Caserne Dossin,Camp,Belgium
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ארון צ'רלס
  Documentation regarding Mosie and Marie (Rothova) Aron, deported from Saint Gilles to Malines, 1943
- Death certificate of Bernhard Sternberg, from Romania, who perished in Mogilev-Podolski, 27/02/1942, 30/08/1948-30/08/1948; 1 Personal documents Death certificate Record of murdered persons Copy, handwritten; O.41/474
  <>,<>,<>,Romania; Mogilev Podolski,Mogilev Podolskiy City,Vinnitsa,Ukraine (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by שטרנברג ישראל
  Death certificate of Bernhard Sternberg, from Romania, who perished in Mogilev-Podolski, 27/02/1942
- List of Jews from Tluste and the Tluste vicinity who perished during the Holocaust, 1965-1965; The file was created by אירגון יוצאי Tluste; 12 Yizkor book List of murdered persons Print; O.41/555
  Tluste,Zaleszczyki,Tarnopol,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by שכנר צבי
  List of Jews from Tluste and the Tluste vicinity who perished during the Holocaust The list was taken from a Yizkor Book.
  The list/s contain approximately 990 names
- Documentation regarding the fate of Berl Karczmann, from Vienna, who perished in Buchenwald, 04/07/1941, date empty; 5 Personal documents Certification Letter Photograph Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/510
  Documentation regarding the fate of Berl Karczmann, from Vienna, who perished in Buchenwald, 04/07/1941 Included in the file are: Photographs of a gravestone, and a letter sent by Karczmann from his place of detention in Vienna to his family members.
- Confirmations from the Czechoslovakian Red Cross and the Relatives Search Bureau of the Jewish Agency regarding the deportation of Gertrude Baer from Prague to Theresienstadt, 24/04/1942, and her transfer to Poland, 09/05/1942, 15/07/1946-20/04/1948; 2 Personal documents Certification Record of deportees xerox; O.41/514
  Praha,Praha Hlavni Mesto,Bohemia,Czechoslovakia; Theresienstadt,Ghetto,Czechoslovakia; <>,<>,<>,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מייזלר יוסף
  Confirmations from the Czechoslovakian Red Cross and the Relatives Search Bureau of the Jewish Agency regarding the deportation of Gertrude Baer from Prague to Theresienstadt, 24/04/1942, and her transfer to Poland, 09/05/1942
- Confirmation by the Dutch Red Cross regarding the fate of Marta (Servos) Cohn, from Eindhoven, who was deported to Westerbork, 29/08/1942 and transferred to Auschwitz, 31/08/1942, where she perished, 03/09/1942, 28/04/1956-28/04/1956; 1 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered persons Typewritten; O.41/483
  Eindhoven,Noordbrabant,<>,The Netherlands; Westerbork,Camp,The Netherlands; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by פרינץ גרשון
  Confirmation by the Dutch Red Cross regarding the fate of Marta (Servos) Cohn, from Eindhoven, who was deported to Westerbork, 29/08/1942 and transferred to Auschwitz, 31/08/1942, where she perished, 03/09/1942
- Application for an entrance visa to British Mandatory Palestine, 1939, by Yehuda Aleksander Drimer, born in Tel Aviv, and including his birth certificate, 21/01/1938-30/01/1939; 3 Personal documents Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/488
  Tel Aviv,<>,<>,British Mandate For Palestine; Stanislawow,Stanislawow,Stanislawow,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by לנגר שולה
  Application for an entrance visa to British Mandatory Palestine, 1939, by Yehuda Aleksander Drimer, born in Tel Aviv, and including his birth certificate - Application for an entrance visa to British Mandatory Palestine, 1939, by Yehuda Aleksander Drimer, who was born in Tel Aviv; - Birth certificate of Yehuda Aleksander Drimer, born in Tel Aviv, 28/11/1937, who returned to Poland with his parents (who were citizens of Poland) when he was 14 months old.
- Confirmation by the Jewish Agency to Lajosne Fenyvesi, regarding the fate of her family members who perished during the Holocaust, 14/05/1946-14/05/1946; The file was created by Jewish Agency for Palestine; 1 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/495
  Sopron,Sopron,<>,Hungary
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אבידור יעקב
  Confirmation by the Jewish Agency to Lajosne Fenyvesi, regarding the fate of her family members who perished during the Holocaust - The fate of Lajos Fenyvesi is unknown; - Edward Fenyvesi perished during the deportation from the hospital in Sopron.
- List of Jews from Wachock, perished and survivors and additional documentation regarding the history of local Jewish community, 1991-1999; 24 List of murdered persons List of survivors Diagram Testimony Survey xerox; O.41/498
  Wachock,Wierzbnik,Kielce,Poland; Wierzbnik,Wierzbnik,Kielce,Poland; Starachowice,Camp
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Feferman Rafael
  List of Jews from Wachock, perished and survivors and additional documentation regarding the history of local Jewish community. Also in file: Pages of Testimony of Feferman families; Sketch of Wachock from 1939; Historical survey on the history of local Jewish community; Testimony of Rafael Ray Feferman about his experiences in Wachock, Wierzbnik and Starachowice camp.
  - List of Jews from Wachock who perished during the Holocaust, including a small number of names of survivors, 1991-1999; 11 List of murdered persons List of survivors; O.41/498.1
    Wachock,Wierzbnik,Kielce,Poland
    List of Jews from Wachock who perished during the Holocaust, including a small number of names of survivors
- Confirmation issued to Isak Gorelik by the Gorodets Council Authority regarding the fate of his family members who were murdered in Rogachev, 1941, 12/01/1944-12/01/1944; 2 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/502
  Gorodets,Rogachev,Gomel,Belorussia (USSR); Rogachev,Rogachev,Gomel,Belorussia (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by גורליק יסאב
  Confirmation issued to Isak Gorelik by the Gorodets Council Authority regarding the fate of his family members who were murdered in Rogachev, 1941
- Confirmation regarding the fate of Abraham Elgrably, born in Casablanca, Morocco, who was deported to Drancy camp, 21/08/1941 and transferred from Drancy to Auschwitz, date empty; 6 Certification Record of deportees Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/551
  Lyon,Rhone,<>,France; Drancy,Camp,France; Auschwitz,Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by אופנהיימר ג.
  Confirmation regarding the fate of Abraham Elgrably, born in Casablanca, Morocco, who was deported to Drancy camp, 21/08/1941 and transferred from Drancy to Auschwitz
- Death certificate of Meyer Van Leeuwen, who perished in Mauthausen, 07/10/1941, and other personal documentation gathered by the submitter of the material, regarding the fate of her relatives from the Netherlands and France who perished during the Holocaust, date empty; 17 Personal documents Certification Death certificate Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/520
  <>,<>,<>,The Netherlands; <>,<>,<>,France
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Salomon-Van Lecuwen Maria
  Death certificate of Meyer Van Leeuwen, who perished in Mauthausen, 07/10/1941, and other personal documentation gathered by the submitter of the material, regarding the fate of her relatives from the Netherlands and France who perished during the Holocaust
- List of the Lisner family members from Zelow who perished, most of them in Chelmno camp, date empty; 1 List of murdered persons xerox; O.41/554
  Zelow,Lask,Lodz,Poland; Chelmno,Extermination Camp,Poland
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by ליסנר בנימין-זאב
  List of the Lisner family members from Zelow who perished, most of them in Chelmno camp
- Documentation regarding the fate of Stern family members from Erfurt who were deported to Belzyce, date empty; 40 Personal documents Certification Yizkor book Record of deportees Record of murdered persons List of persecuted persons xerox; O.41/544
  Erfurt,Erfurt,Saxony Province,Germany; Belzyce,Ghetto; Birkenfeld,Trier,Rhine Province,Germany; Bad Kreuznach,Koblenz,Rhine Province,Germany
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by שטרן שאול ולטר
  Documentation regarding the fate of Stern family members from Erfurt who were deported to Belzyce Included in the file: - Partial lists from the Yizkor book of Bad Kreuznach and Birkenfeld.
- List of residents of Mozyr who perished, 1941-1945, Список мирных жителей г. Мозыря, сожженных, расстрелянных, уничтоженных в период Великой Отечественной войны 1941-1945 гг; date empty; 6 List of murdered persons Newspaper clippings Original and Xerox; O.41/475
  Mozyr,Mozyr City,Polesye,Belorussia (USSR)
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by מוזיקנטסקי אהרון
  List of residents of Mozyr who perished, 1941-1945 Prepared for the publication of a memorial book in 1997.
- Confirmation from the Dutch Red Cross regarding the fate of the members of the Simons family and Ezra Levisson from the Netherlands, deported in 1943 and perished in Sobibor and Auschwitz, 26/06/1946-26/06/1946; The file was created by Het Nederlandsche Roode Kruis; 1 Personal documents Certification Record of deportees Record of murdered persons Typewritten; O.41/480
  Confirmation from the Dutch Red Cross regarding the fate of the members of the Simons family and Ezra Levisson from the Netherlands, deported in 1943 and perished in Sobibor and Auschwitz
- Decision by the Court of Law in Berlin Spandau, establishing that the date of death of the couple, Henry Stargardter and Emma (Kassel) Stargardter, from Berlin, was on 30/12/1942, 30/09/1947-30/09/1947; 1 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered persons Official documentation xerox; O.41/511
  Decision by the Court of Law in Berlin Spandau, establishing that the date of death of the couple, Henry Stargardter and Emma (Kassel) Stargardter, from Berlin, was on 30/12/1942
- Birth certificate of Rudolf Rozenberg, from Rogoz, 18/04/1950-18/04/1950; 14 Personal documents Photograph xerox; O.41/484
  Rogoz,Somes,Transylvania,Romania
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by הלר ליאה
  Birth certificate of Rudolf Rozenberg, from Rogoz Included in the file are: Copies of family photographs.
- Burial certificate of Wilhelm Bern from Vienna, Austria who died on 25/02/1939, date empty; 1 Personal documents Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/487
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by Kainz Eva
  Burial certificate of Wilhelm Bern from Vienna, Austria who died on 25/02/1939
- Inquiry into the fate of members of the Zaibel family from Riga who perished in the Holocaust, date empty; 1 Record of murdered persons Letter Typewritten; O.41/492
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by זייבל מיכאל
  Inquiry into the fate of members of the Zaibel family from Riga who perished in the Holocaust
- Confirmations regarding the fate of the Iciks Izakson family members from Riga who perished during the Holocaust, from the National Archives of Latvia, 1991-1997, 1991-1997; 5 Personal documents Certification Record of murdered persons xerox; O.41/499
  The materials were transferred to Yad Vashem by דינר חסיה
  Confirmations regarding the fate of the Iciks Izakson family members from Riga who perished during the Holocaust, from the National Archives of Latvia, 1991-1997
- Confirmations regarding the deportation of Rozsa Widder Rosenberg from Budapest, 23/10/1944, 29/01/1948-30/12/1956; 2 Personal documents Certification xerox; O.41/517
  Budapest,Pest-Pilis-Solt-Kiskun,<>,Hungary; <>,<>,<>,Germany
  Confirmations regarding the deportation of Rozsa Widder Rosenberg from Budapest, 23/10/1944